<resources>
    <string name="app_name">2D Bulusan Flood Forecasting</string>

    <string-array name="array_zone">
        <item>Select Zone</item>
        <item>Zone 1</item>
        <item>Zone 2</item>
        <item>Zone 3</item>
        <item>Zone 4</item>
        <item>Zone 5</item>
        <item>Zone 6</item>
        <item>Zone 7</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="array_duration">
        <item>Select Duration</item>
        <item>1 Hour</item>
        <item>3 Hour</item>
        <item>6 Hour</item>
        <item>12 Hour</item>
        <item>24 Hour</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="select">
        <item>Select Intensity</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="light">
        <b>ADVISORY (Community AWARENESS)</b>\n
        Flooding is POSSIBLE in low-lying areas and near river channels.
    </string>

    <string name="moderate">
        <b>ALERT (Community PREPAREDNESS)</b>\n
        Flooding is THREATENING in low-lying areas and near river channels.
    </string>

    <string name="heavy">
        <b>EMERGENCY (Community RESPONSE)</b>\n
        SEVERE Flooding is EXPECTED. Take precautionary measures.
    </string>

    <string name="lightTitle">
        <b>Light Rain</b>
    </string>
    <string name="moderateTitle">
        <b>Moderate Rain</b>
    </string>
    <string name="heavyTitle">
        <b>Heavy Rain</b>
    </string>

    <string name="infoLight">
        -Individual drops easily identified and puddles(small muddy pools) form slowly.\n
        -Small streams may flow in gutters.\n\n\n

        Would you like to read the <b>Flood Safety Rules</b>?
    </string>

    <string name="infoModerate">
        -Puddles rapidly forming and down pipes flowing freely.\n\n\n

        Would you like to read the <b>Flood Safety Rules</b>?
    </string>

    <string name="infoHeavy">
        -The sky is overcast, there is a continuous precipitation.\n
        -Falls in sheets, misty spray over hard surfaces.\n
        -May cause roaring noise on roofs.\n\n\n

        Would you like to read the <b>Flood Safety Rules</b>?
    </string>

    <string name="zone1_info">
        <b>Zone 1 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 50\n
        Families: 53\n
        Male: 122\n
        Female: 160\n
        Total Population: 282
    </string>

    <string name="zone2_info">
        <b>Zone 2 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 54\n
        Families: 54\n
        Male: 115\n
        Female: 116\n
        Total Population: 231
    </string>

    <string name="zone3_info">
        <b>Zone 3 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 69\n
        Families: 71\n
        Male: 175\n
        Female: 160\n
        Total Population: 335
    </string>

    <string name="zone4_info">
        <b>Zone 4 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 60\n
        Families: 64\n
        Male: 175\n
        Female: 155\n
        Total Population: 330
    </string>

    <string name="zone5_info">
        <b>Zone 5 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 49\n
        Families: 54\n
        Male: 123\n
        Female: 128\n
        Total Population: 251
    </string>

    <string name="zone6_info">
        <b>Zone 6 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 94\n
        Families: 97\n
        Male: 275\n
        Female: 273\n
        Total Population: 548
    </string>

    <string name="zone7_info">
        <b>Zone 7 Info:</b>\n
        Houses: 63\n
        Families: 67\n
        Male: 173\n
        Female: 143\n
        Total Population: 316
    </string>

    <string-array name="one">
        <item>Select Intensity</item>
        <item>Light (2.5 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Moderate (2.5–7.5 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Heavy (>7.5 mm/Hr)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="three">
        <item>Select Intensity</item>
        <item>Light (7.5 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Moderate (7.5–22.5 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Heavy (>22.5 mm/Hr)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="six">
        <item>Select Intensity</item>
        <item>Light (15 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Moderate (15–45 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Heavy (>45 mm/Hr)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="twelve">
        <item>Select Intensity</item>
        <item>Light (30 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Moderate (30–90 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Heavy (>90 mm/Hr)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="twentyfour">
        <item>Select Intensity</item>
        <item>Light (60 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Moderate (60–180 mm/Hr)</item>
        <item>Heavy (>180 mm/Hr)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="flood_rules">
        <text align="justify">
        <b>BEFORE THE FLOOD:</b>\n\n

        \u2022Find out how often your location is likely to be flooded.\n
        \u2022Know the flood warning system in your community and be sure your family knows it.\n
        \u2022Keep informed of daily weather condition.\n
        \u2022Designate an evacuation area for the family and livestock.\n
        \u2022Assign family members instructions and responsibilities according to an evacuation plan.\n
        \u2022Keep a stock of food which requires little cooking and refrigeration; electric power may be interrupted.\n
        \u2022Keep a transistorized radio and flashlight with spare batteries, emergency cooking equipment, candles, matches and first aid kit handy in case of emergency.\n
        \u2022Store supplies and other household effects above expected flood water level.\n
        \u2022Securely anchor weak dwellings and items.\n\n

        <b>WHEN WARNED OF FLOOD:</b>\n\n

        \u2022Watch for rapidly rising flood waters.Listen to your radio for emergency instructions.\n
        \u2022If you find it necessary to evacuate, move to a safe area before access is cut off by flood waters.\n
        \u2022Store drinking water in containers, water service may be interrupted.\n
        \u2022Move household belongings to upper levels.\n
        \u2022Get livestock to higher ground.\n
        \u2022Turn off electricity at the main switch in the building before evacuating and also lock your house.\n\n

        <b>DURING THE FLOOD:</b>\n\n

        \u2022Avoid areas subject to sudden flooding.\n
        \u2022Do not attempt to cross rivers of flowing streams where water is above the knee.\n
        \u2022Beware of water-covered roads and bridges.Avoid unnecessary exposure to the elements.\n
        \u2022Do not go swimming or boating in swollen rivers.Eat only well-cooked food. Protect leftovers against contamination.\n
        \u2022Drink clean or preferably boiled water ONLY.\n\n

        <b>AFTER THE FLOOD:</b>\n\n

        \u2022Re-enter the dwellings with caution using flashlights, not lanterns or torchers. Flammables may be inside.\n
        \u2022Be alert for fire hazards like broken wires.\n
        \u2022Do not eat food and drink water until they have been checked for flood water contamination.\n
        \u2022Report broken utility lines(electricity, water, gas and telephone) to appropriate agencies authorities.\n
        \u2022Do not turn on the main switch or use appliances and other equipment until they have been checked by a competent electrician.\n
        \u2022Consult health authorities for immunization requirements.\n
        \u2022Do not go in disaster areas. Your presence might hamper rescue and other emergency operations.\n\n

        Flood are aggravated by factors resulting from the carelessness and indifference of people usually before floods occur.\n\n

        <b>THINGS ONE CAN DO TO MITIGATE FLOODS:</b>\n\n

        \u2022Regulate cutting of trees.\n
        \u2022Report illegal loggers and kaingeros.\n
        \u2022Report illegal construction of fishponds and other establishments in waterways.\n
        \u2022Do not throw garbage in esteros and rivers.Help clean the neighborhood.\n
        \u2022Support community activities intended to lessen the occurrence of floods.\n
        \u2022Avoid throwing anything like plastic wrappers anywhere which may clog or block the drainage system.\n
        </text>
        </string>

    <string name="instructions">
        <b>Here are the basic steps in using the app:</b>\n\n
        1. First, search for a zone.\n\n
        2. Then, set the Duration of the rain.\n\n
        3. Different mm/Hr will be displayed for each Intensity depending on the Duration selected. Select one.\n\n
        4.  After that, click the START button to show result.\n\n
        5. A pop-up will show containing a warning message with a background color corresponding for the Intensity of rain: <b>Yellow</b> for Light, <b>Orange</b> for Moderate, and <b>Red</b> for Heavy.\n\n
        6. Along with the warning message is a dialog box that describes the Intensity selected, with an option to read the Flood Safety Rules containing the Do\'s and Don\'ts before, during and after a flood.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="about">
        <b><font size="20">About the Developers</font></b>\n\n
        <b>Programmer:</b>\u0020John Mari Ocampo\n\n
        <b>Analyst:</b>\u0020Khristine N. Vibar\n\n
        <b>Project Manager:</b>\u0020Bernard Joseph N. Mier\n\n
        <b>Testing:</b>\u0020Loren Bucad\n\n

        <b><font size="20">About this App</font></b>\n\n
        <b>THIS APP IS DESIGNED FOR THE RESIDENTS OF BRGY. BULUSAN ONLY.</b>\n\n
        The purpose of this app is to help the residents of Brgy. Bulusan forecast a flood by searching for their house and providing rain information such as duration and intensity.\n\n

        <b><font size="20">History of Bulusan</font></b>\n\n
        Nagkaroon ng pagkakakilanlan ang Barangay na ito bilang daluyan o "bubulusan" ng baha na nanggagaling sa kabundukan ng Brgy. San Jose sa
        dakong timog at Brgy. Bacolod Quimba River sa bandang silangan. Natatabunan ng makakapal na atalahib ang malawak nitong kapatagan na siyang pinamumugaran
        ng baboy ramo at iba pang ligaw na hayop. Bago pumasok ang ika-20 siglo, naging hanapbuhay ng mga tagarito and pangingisda tuwing tag-ulan at pangangaso
        naman kung tag-init.\n\n

        Sa pag-unlad ng sibilisasyon pinalitang ng "Bulusan" ang pangalan nitong "bubulusan". Idinirekta din itong "indipendente" bilang bagong Barangay
        noong 1920 at nahirang na cabeza de Barangay nung kapanahunan ni Mariano Sario. Pinagtulungan din ng mga tao na itayo ang simbahan ng Sta. Cruz
        Patron ng Barangay noong ika-3 ng Mayo, kung saan ipinagdiriwang ang kapistahan ng Sta. Cruz. Sumunod na hinirang na cabeza de Barangay si Loriano Bron.
        Sa nasabing posisyon ng Sta. Cruz pinag-yaman ng mga tao ang kanilang paniniwala sa pamamagitan ng makulay na Dta. Cruz taong 1943 sa pamamahala ni Flora
        Bron at Jacinto Cerdena. Naging tradisyonal na ito sa mahabang panahon. Di naglaon pinamunuan din ang Barangay na ito ng anim na tiniente del barrio.\n\n


        <b><font size="20">Learn more</font></b>\n\n
        About Bulusan:\n<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libon,_Albay">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libon,_Albay</a>\n\n
        Pag-asa Official Twitter (@dost_pagasa):\n<a href="https://twitter.com/dost_pagasa?lang=en">https://twitter.com/dost_pagasa?lang=en</a>\n\n
        Pag-asa Official Facebook Page:\n<a href="https://www.facebook.com/PAGASA.DOST.GOV.PH/">https://www.facebook.com/PAGASA.DOST.GOV.PH/</a>\n\n
        Pag-asa Official Website:\n<a href="https://www1.pagasa.dost.gov.ph">https://www1.pagasa.dost.gov.ph</a>\n
    </string>


</resources>
